Guide to the International Monitor Institute. Burma Videotapes, circa 1990-2002 RL.00605
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Burma Videotapes, circa 1990-2002, 287 videocassettes
  - NHK: Burma on the Brink, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 290, Video-cassette BU260)
    Daw Aung San Suu Kyi: "If the majority is poor, I do not wish to be rich."
    U Than Maung, Unity Development Party: "Democracy is to be built slowly, economy first. Democracy is not to be demanded, like it has fallen from the sky. Democracy is not a material thing. I love Daw Aung San Suu Kyi. I love Union of Myanmar more."
    A child working with daily wages.
    Daw Aung San Suu Kyi: "Human rights is human right." "Chicken and egg situation." "
    Businessman: "Multi national corporations won't come even if Daw Aung San Suu Kyi takes power."
    SLORC's ceasefire. Never three groups together.
    U Tin Oo: "1990 election should be honored. We are not for forming government. Japan may be sincere."
    Bangkok, All Burma Students' Democratic Front (ABSDF) hideout. Aung Htoo: "Releasing her is not enough. All prisoners must be released. Nationwide ceasefire should be called and start national reconciliation process.
    Where is Burma heading? Mitta.
    When SLORC's will to economic development and Suu Kyi's way of human rights meets, democracy will be realized.
    NHK clips.
    Daw Aung San Suu Kyi at "Martyrs' Day."
  - Amateur Footage: Burmese patriots in Japan (1988), NTSC VHS [TRT 00:15:00] (2 copies) (Box 290, Video-cassette BU261)
    Produced by: Private (A Burmese from Japan)
    Dr. Kyaw Tint, working as an activist.
    City of Tokyo: A meeting with other people.
    "We must demonstrate because we are not threatened or shot-at, like people inside Burma."
    Peaceful demonstration is better.
    U Min Nyo: A demonstration in Japan: Ne Win Gets Out, Saw Maung a Bob Cat. Kill Sein Lwin. Victory to democratic struggle.
  - HRTV: Rights and Wrongs in Burma, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:27:00] (2 copies) (Box 298, Video-cassette BU262)
    Produced by: HRTV
    Burma a human rights nightmare.
    A Shin Byu water festival Fha Wah Ta "Keep Quiet Regime"
    An army fortress, Military crushed the people's uprising.
    Extensive foreign investment. Mon and Karen rebels.
    Naing Tun Myint: "SLORC has beef up security."
    Refugee camps.
    Saley Thompson: "Burma Border consortium avoid forced porterage, human mine sweepers.
    Hte Aung: "The armyusesus asmine sweepers."
    Everyone over 15 is taken,e ven those who are pregnant and sick. Many died of abuse and harsh treatment.
    Forced labor situation. Atrocities committedby army.
    Former soldiers punished for refusing to shoot. Students.
    Manplaw, Bo Mya: "SLORC is not sincere at all."
    All Burma Students' Democratic Front (ABSDF)headquarters.
    Dr. Myint Chu: "Most Burmese do not know about human rights inside. Oppression was obvious."
    In spite of growing international recognition, the regime continues to enslave its own people.
    State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC)reply: "No comment."
  - Karen Hero's Day Celebration and Reunion, Bakersfield CA Interviewwith Robert Zan, Commander Karen National Union (KNU) (Los Angeles ), NTSC VHS [TRT 00:45:00] ((2 copies) (Box 290 and 298, Video-cassette BU263)
    Produced by: International Monitoring Institute (IMI) Analyst
    Karen Baptist Fellowship, Bakersfield, California
    Worship service honoring heroes of Karen wars and peace.
    Musical numbers, Kids, Women's group musical numbers. Robert White - Student researcher
    Family friend's home; Saw Wei. Interview Maj. Robert Zan: "My father was a founder of Karen revolution movement KNDO. Since 1945 I was UG, then in 1964 I joined KNDO. I served several positions and placesin KNU. We do not kill prisoners of war. This is the biggest difference from State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC) army. We allow him to defect or send him home. Burmese army rapes the female captives but we never do that. We are brothers not enemies. We must be different from enemy otherwisewe do not need to fight. My youngest brother died in the war. I sought revenge in blood. In a decisive victory I had my revenge. I realized that I had killed my brothers. I thought it was not the solution.
    Open the second letter to Daw Aung San Suu Kyi.
    Army needs to know about human rights abuses.
    Refugee's situation, true story: No one wants to leave home. Refugee camps are like concentration camps. Our strategy is people-based, so enemy tries to eradicate people. Enemy is very destructive. Atrocities are beyond human imagination.
    SLORC's policy is to block our barrel with people's hands. It is ten times worse than fascist Japanese.
    Totally intolerable situation, people leaving home.
  - International Rescue Commtitee (IRC): Refugees under IRC, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (Box 298, Video-cassette BU264)
    Produced by: IRC
    Hospital Project, Mother and Child Care Project.
  - Japanese TV: Return of the Worrier (August 1996), NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 298, Video-cassette BU265)
    Produced by: Japanese TV
    A trip to reunite All Burma Students' Democratic Front (ABSDF)
    Investment boom in Burma; Aung San Suu Kyi has called for sanctions. Htun Aung Gya, former ABSDF chairman, returned to front line after 5 years.
    Luxuries of Ne Win: "Although he knew developments abroad, he kept Burmese people in the darkness."
    A meeting with ABSDF colleagues; cracks in politics
    Only one remaining camp - Min Tha Mee: the Burma side of the border, a rough road.
    Freedom fighters; "Raise Your Head Brothers" - an ABSDF song
    Lives of students on the front.
    I worried about Suu Kyi. She is among the wolves. But she says: "Do not worry about me. Be united."
    Disunited groups dispersed in Thailand. Tun Aung Gyaw made an attempt to reunite them.
    Madam Mya going fishing.
    A meeting with General Mya: "Everything is the plot of SLORC. Spies spread rumors. We do not oppress Buddhists."
    Border bridge; Young vendors; Dr. Cynthia Maung's clinic; Interview with porters; Stories of torture and abuse.
    Refugee camps and their agony.
    Waste of humanity: Prostitutes in Thai land at age of not more than 17.
    Karanni Refugees; Atrocities of army
    Ray Aung - Karanni Information Minister: "SLORC does not keep promises."
    Nain Aung - ABSDF Chairman
  - International Rescue Commtitee (IRC): Refugees under IRC, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (Box 290, Video-cassette BU266)
    IRC inspection team; hospital and school; women's projects.
  - Singapore Sling, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:33:00] (2 copies) (Box 290, Video-cassette BU267)
    Produced by: SBS Australia, Date Line
    Mike Carry: Singapore is the least corrupted country in Asia.
    Lee Kwan Yoo: "We set up the system to ensure mutual vigilance and maintain high standards of integrity and competence. But I believe that more important than the institution is a culture of an honest government that we have established."
    Singapore investment - Burma's biggest partner
    Dr. Chee Soon Juan (the opposition party): "Singapore hangs drug traffickers. Why should we engage with SLORC that is connected with drug trafficking? We have to ask ourselves."
    General Than Shwe pays a visit to Go Chauk Thong.
    Singapore government funds directly involved with drug lord business from Burma.
    Kwak Singapore; Mr. Kwak - the tycoon; Dealing with Burma; Traders and Shangrhila hotels
    Myanmar fund Limited with Thailand Halpin Ho
    Lo Sit Han - a drug lord
    Bertil Litner: "Lo Sit Han is international bandit."
    Lo Sit Han and Khin Nyunt; In 1993, Lo Sit Han shipped heroin with the permission of Khin Nyunt," according to investigators from the Thailand Narcotic Department.
    Australia Drug Enforcement Agency: "Lo Sit Han is a major drug producer controlling the entire trade.
    Stephen Lo was denied US visa. Cecilia Ng: "No comment."
    Stephen Lo: "No comment. I need to rush to the airplane. No involvement in drugs."
    Burma: Shwedagon Pagoda
    Lo's business: Asia World Company; Kokang Import and Export Company
    Dr. Sein Win: "Drug lords invest heavily in Burma and it is laundering."
    Singapore Connection: "GSIC" - Government of Singapore Investment Corporation
    Dr. Gary Rodan of Murdoch University: "Tracking GSIC record is successful. We carefully chose partners, but it is top secret."
    Irish Stock Exchange on Myanmar Fund - the largest share holderis GSIC
    Three months after INSANCO replaced GSIC
    Although it is not illegal it is something to do with integrity.
    Dr. Sein Win. "If you deal with a Drug Lord it is funny. Where did Lo Sit Han get money?"
    Go Chauk Tong is not on the GSIC board.
    Chang Ri Prison "hung over 60 people for drug offenses."
    Dr. Sein Win: "Those small men got caught and got hung. Big fishes go free and rich."
    Asia World Group
    Aung San Suu Kyi, State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC) cabinet, and Than Shwe and Go Chauk Tung
  - AV Media: Tribal Dances of Burma, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:60:00] (2 copies) (Box 290, Video-cassette BU268)
    Produced by: AV Media and Win Tin Tin's Presence
    Dances from various regions and ethnicities of Burma
    Chin Dance: A Circle Dance; a group of girls.
    Sword Dance over the bulls' skull
    Dawai(Tavoy): Group of girls Yane
    Inn Tharr: Lancedee
    Kachin: Group dance. Everyone participates.
    Kayah: Padong dance
    Karen: Dance of unity and strength
    Lisu: New year dance.
    Mons: Girls only. No public participation.
    Yakhine
    Shan
  - Amateur Footage: Nintieth Birthday of Dictator Ne Win, NTSC VHS [TRT 02:00:00] (Box 290, Video-cassette BU269)
    March 21, 2001, Sedona Hotel.
    Guests arrive: Former cabinet members of Burma Socialist Program Party.
    U Ye Gaung, U Saw Phyu, U Chit Hlaing, and widows, too. Col Maung Maung Aye.
    Former chairman U Sein Lwin was seen (allegedly responsible for 6 thousand deaths in 1988)
    Three notorious grandsons: Kyaw Ne Win, Aye Ne Win, Zwe Ne Win.
  - Amateur Footage: Interview with Victims of Tamadaw Abuses, 1999, NTSC VHS [TRT 01:00:00] (Box 293, Video-cassette BU270)
  - International Rescue Commtitee (IRC): Rihingers in Bangladesh, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:36:00] (2 copies) (Box 293, Video-cassette BU271)
    Cox Bazar port full of displaced Rohinger from Burma.
  - APTV: Footage from Burma, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (Box 293, Video-cassette BU272)
    Karen National Union (KNU) soldiers at war. Bo Mya the leader. Refugee camps on the hillsides. Use of chemical weapons against Karen civilians by Burmese army. Stories of atrocities.
  - Presentation for Pepperdine University, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:05:00] (Box 293, Video-cassette BU273)
    Produced by: International Monitoring Institute (IMI) Edited
    Burma's General Condition for presentation related to Pepperdine Week of Justice.
  - Amateur Footage: Testimony on Massacre (1988), NTSC VHS [TRT 00:24:00] (Box 293, Video-cassette BU274)
    Private Hla Thaung: Infantry 16 Division 22. Detail on North Okkalapa Massacre by army. It is estimated that more than 40,000 have been killed. Rangoon mortuary piled up tens of thousands of bodies killed by soldiers.
    Bodies were cremated and crematorium was overloaded. Some bodies fed to the crocodiles. Dumped in the sea. They don't want to see any living thing in the streets.
  - TV Myanmar: State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC)'s version of 1998 People's Uprising (Poor Quality Video), NTSC VHS [TRT 01:00:00] (2 copies) (Box 293, Video-cassette BU275)
    Communists and foreign powers are blamed for 1988 massacre. Denial of any wrong doing by Tatmadaw.
  - Amateur Footage: National League for Democracy (NLD) CEO and Daw Suu Attacked by Thugs, NTSC Betacam SP [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 293, Video-cassette BU276)
    Broken windshield of Daw Suu's car. Bloody noses of U Tin Oo and U Kyi Maung. People's support of NLD is obvious.
  - The Land of Pagoda, NTSC VHS [TRT 01:00:00] (Box 293, Video-cassette BU277)
    Produced by: AV Media Limited
    Network: Private
    Weaving Contest in Shwedagonom Tazaungpone Fullmoon day
    Scenes across delta, a village wedding, a Buddhist novication ceremony.
    Th city of charoot Bago (Pegu). Kyaik Htee Yoo. Burmese Boxing. A family with snake pet.
    Mandalay, dances, Thanakha phenomenum. Hill tribes of Shan State.
    Music from Burmese harp.
  - Burma. Lost Memories, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:58:00] (Box 293, Video-cassette BU278)
    Produced by: Sceneries Distribution
    The most in depth and detailed account of Burma ever made!
    Burmese government is guilty of exploiting its people to the point of socio-economic ruin.
    Interview with Daw Aung San Suu Kyi.
  - Interview Jocelyn Seagrave, Burma Forum LA, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:12:00] (2 copies) (Box 293 and 294, Video-cassette BU279)
    Produced by: International Monitoring Institute, Souteast Aisa Archive
    I want to see Burma prosper and free. It is my grandfather's mother land. Foreign investment would prolong the army dictatorship in Burma
  - Interview with Kyaw Myat Oo, Ko Latt, Burma Forum Los Angeles (BFLA), All Burma Students' Democratic Front (ABSDF), NTSC VHS [TRT 00:34:00] (2 copies) (Box 294, Video-cassette BU280)
    Produced by: International Monitoring Institute Southeast Asia Archive
    "I saw many killed on the streets, blood everywhere... I am so scared.I fought Burmese army."
  - Interview with Daw Nu NU Yi, Burma Forum Los Angeles (BFLA), Rangoon Resident, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:35:00] (2 copies) (Box 294, Video-cassette BU281)
    Produced by: International Monitoring Institute Southeast Asia Archive Archive
    "I witnessed the economic down fall of Burma under the SLORC. Brothers jailed and fled. Broken hearted mother. Need unity to fight the dictator."
  - Interview with Zaw Lun, National League for Democracy (NLD) Los Angeles, Karen National Union (KNU), NTSC VHS [TRT 00:35:00] (2 copies) (Box 294, Video-cassette BU282)
    Government is to be blamed for economic and social demise in Burma.
  - Unocal Share Holder Meeting 2002, May 20, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:20:00] (2 copies) (Box 294, Video-cassette BU283)
    Produced by: International Monitoring Institute Southeast Aisa Archive
    Demonstration in heavy rain. People chanted. "Unocal out of Burma."
  - Unocal Protest Rally by GHAP, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:37:00] (Box 294, Video-cassette BU284)
    Produced by: GHAP Exclusive
    Students, Activists, Labor Unions joined protest rally against Unocal. Brea, California.
  - Cynthia Maung's Presentation at Los Angeles for GHAP, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:52:00] (Box 294, Video-cassette BU285)
    Produced by: International Monitoring Institute Webmaster
    Cynthia Maung's clinic and situation, Q & A and a lot of fun.
  - Interview with migrant worker Nan San Myint, 2002 June 16, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:20:00] (Box 294, Video-cassette BU286)
    Produced by: International Monitoring Institute Southeast Asia Desk
    Conditions behind the Burmese migrant workers in Thailand.
  - Rangoon Steel, PAL Hi-8 [TRT 00:10:00] (Box 294, Video-cassette BU287)
  - GHAP production on Burma, 2002 May, PAL Hi-8 [TRT 00:10:00] (Box 294, Video-cassette BU288)
  - "Freedom is Precious": Interview with Daw Aung San Suu Kyi, 1999 Nov. 29, PAL Hi-8 [TRT 00:50:00] (Box 294, Video-cassette BU289)
    Produced by: Nancy Andersen
    Includes 15 minutes of "Highlights from 'Freedom is Precious'"